Finding Aid for the Jesse Ely Wills Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Memorandum on Fugitive Room in the New Wing of the Joint University Library; F. 6-13. This is a name index of the correspondents of Jesse Ely Wills. The figure (or figures) in parentheses immediately following each name denotes the total number of letters from that person in the collection; the da
Force, William W., (1); 2 June 1970; F. 1-7.
Fowler, S. Benjamin, (1); 21 April 1960 (to William F. Orr, Jr.); F. 6-19.
Gardner, Edwin S., (2); 19 June 1968; F. 1-8. 22 August 1971; F. 6-13.
Gardner, Robert L., (3); 13 November 1967; F. 6-13. 2 November 1970; 30 November 1970; F. 6-8.
Geny, Charles W., (1); 5 April 1968; F. 6-7.
Gibbs, Homer B., Jr., (1); 9 October 1969 (to Rob Roy Purdy); F. 6-10.
Gordon, Caroline, (2); 18 April 1959; 11 May 1959; F. 1-8.
Gower, Herschel, (1); 21 February 1972; F. 1-8.
Gray, William Dixon, (1); 25 May 1959;F. 3-5.
Grisham, Frank P., (15); 7 December 1967 (to Woodrow Wasson); 7 October 1968; 8 August 1969 (to Madison Wigginton); 27 August 1969; F. 6-13. 9 January 1969; 14 February 1969 (to Alex B. Stevenson); 17 March 1969; F. 6-5. 6 February 1970 a(to Executive Committee Board of Library Trustees; Joint
Faculty Library Committee); 17 February 1971; F. 6-13.a 19 October 1971 (to Mrs. Mapheus Smith); 26 December 1973; 18 January 1974; 25 May 1976; 10 August 1976; 2 November 1976; F. 1-8.
Haddock, Susan Abney, (3); 7 June 1972; 13 June 1972; F. 6-13. 3November 1972; F. 1-8.
Hall, Howard R., (3); 13 March 1959 (to Lester Smith); 27 March 1959
Hall, May and Dave, (1); 7 February 1960; F. 3-5.
Hamner, Gustavus A.H., (1); 10 November 1969 (to Alexander Heard); F. 6-10.
Harrelson, Walter, (5); 7 April 1970 (to Nicholas Hobbs); F. 6-6. 14 November 1973; 27 November 1973; 11 JanuarY 1974; 11 March 1974; F. 6-9.
Harrison, Charles E., Jr., (1); 10 October 1969 (to Executive
Committee Board of Trust); F. 6-10.
Harrison, Randolph, (2); 4 May 1959; F. 3-5. 2 August 1968; F. 1-8.
Heard, Alexander, (23); 11 June 1965 (to Fort Flowers); 12 June 1965; 22 June 1965; 10 July 1965 (to Fort Flowers); 30 November 1965 (to Fort Flowers); 6 May 1966; F. 6-12. 20 November 1966; 29 November 1966 (to Members of the Vanderbilt Board of Trust); 30 January 1968; F. 6-7. 8 November 1968 (to Members of the Special Committee of the Board of Trust to aStudy the University~s Long-Range Financing); F • 6-15. 31 December 1968; F. 6-5. 9 January 1970; F. 6-6. 10 January 1970; 14 January 1970; 21 January 1970 (to William s. V~~hn); 22 January 1970; F. 6-2. 24 March 1970; F. 6-6- 16 May 1970 (to Dean Christman, Dean Holladay and Dean Row~, 12 May 1970); 4 July 1970 (telegram); F. 6-2. 5 November 1970; 19 November 1970; F. 6-13. 25 October 1971; F. 6-4. n.d.; F. 1-8.Heathco, Dan D., (1); 10 September 1976; F. 1-8.
Hecht, Anthony, (1); 29 December 1975; F. 5-3.
Heffernan, Thomas F., (1); 9 April 1969; F. 1-8.
Hendley, Tillie Clare (Mrs. Joseph Owen), (1); 29 May 1959; F. 3-5.
Hill, Horace G., Jr., (2); 26 May 1965; 16 June 1965; F. 6-12.
Hirsch, Sidney Mttron, (1); 18 April 1959; F. 3-5.Hobbs, Nicholas, (12); 24 June 1969; 1 August 1969; 16 September 1969; 24 September 1969; 3 February 1970; 10 February 1970; 18 March 1970; 22 September 1970; 21 October 1970; F. 6-2. 12 February 1971; 12 March 1971; F. 6-8. 19 November 1973; F. 6-9.
Holbrook, Morton, III, (1); 22 September 1969 (to Alexander Heard); F. 6-10.a
Holter, Bob, (1); 5 January 1961 (to William F. Orr, Jr.), (telegram); F. 6-19.
Houston, Frank K., (1); 17 July 1967 (mimeograph report); F. 1-8.
Hunt, Edwin, (1); 28 April 1967; F. 1-8. Lmpastato, David J., (1); 3 January 1961 (to William F. Orr); F. 6-19.
Ingram, E.B., (1); 21 September 1973; F. 6-17.
Jarman, W. Maxey, (2); 13 April 1959; F. 3-8. 12 August 1970; F. 1-8.
Jewett, James E., (1); 23 June 1976; F. 6-11.
Johnson; Wictor"S., Jr., (1); 11 March 1971; F. 1-8.
Jones, David Howell, (1); 3 February 1966; F. 1-8.
Jordan, Polly (Mrs. Robert H.), (1); 26 May 1959; F. 3-5.
Kaser, David, (10); 22 June 1965; 18 March 1966; 25 March 1966 (to Alec B. Stevenson); 27 April 1966 (to Committee on the
Development of the Gradua"te Wing, Board o~ Trustees); F. 6-12. 23 May 1966; F. 6-13. 12 December 1967; F. 1-8. 15 July 1968 (to Andrew Lytle); 23 May 1968; 30 May 1968 (to Andrew Lytle); F. 6-13. n.d. (to Committee on the Development of a Library a Wing, Board of Trustees); F. 6-12.
Kellam, James R., III, (1); 29 September 1969; F. 6-10.Kirkendall, Ralph, (1); 8 April 1971 (to Donald Thist1ethwaite); F. 6-4.
Kolb, Lawrence C., (1); 10 January 1961 (to William F. Orr); F. 6-19.
Kuhlman, A. Frederick, (1); 14 October 1975; F. 6-12.
Light, Rudolph A., (3); 26 June 1969; 19 September 1969; 28 October 1969; F. 6-2.
Lipscomb, Anne C. (Mrs. A. Brant), (1); 11 November 1969 (to Committee on Undergraduate Affairs); F. 6-10.
Lockert, C. Lacy, (1); 21 November 1958 (to Rob Roy Purdy); F. 3-4.
Lytle, Andrew, (1); 20 May 1959; F. 3-5. 5 October 1963; 1 February a1968; 20 February 1968; 11 July 1969; 10 April 1913; 24 August 1913; F. 1-8.
McAlister, Bill, (1); 3 May 1959; F. 3-5.
McCall, Gertie (Mrs. John T.); 12 April 1959; F. 3-5.
McDonnell, Carolyn, (1); 11 May 1969; F. 1-9.
McGaw, Robert A., (9); 11 December 1958; F. 3-4. 5 June 1959 (to
Lester Smith); F. 6-19. 26 October 1961; F •. 6-11. 15 June 1916;,8 September 1916; 10 September 1916 (Question Fo~); 11 September 1916; 21 September 1916; 23 September 1916; F. 5-9.
Mackenzie, Kenneth W., (1); 3 October 1969 (to Executive Committee of the Board of Trust); F. 6-10.
Mann, Delbert, (2); 13 September 1969; 23 October 1969; F. 6-2.
Manning, Nancy Jane, (3); 1 July 1969 (to William Vaughn); 25 October 1969; n.d.; F. 6-2.
Massey, Richard, (1); 1 November 1958 (to William F. Orr); F. 6-19.
Master, Barry L., (1); 10 November 1911; F. 6-4.
Meyer, Audrey, (1); 12 March 1916 (to Jane C. Tensley); F. 5-3.
Moore, Adam, (1); 1 June 1968; F. 1-9.
Moore, Ann Leslie (Mrs. Merrill), (6); 24 April 1959; F. 3-5. 1 June 1968; 1 July 1968; 6 February 1969; 24 February 1969;28 May 1910; F. 1-9.
Moore, Merrill, (1)'; 20 August 1952; F. 1-9.Moriarty, Wilson P. (Pat), (1); 30 September 1969 (to Mr. Purdy); F. 6-10. Niles, Henry E., (1); 28 November 1966; F. 1-9.
Orr, William F., (12); 21 July 1956; 15 November 1956; 12 November 1951 a(to Seymour D. Vestermark); 23 September 1958 (to John W.
Patterson); 1 January 1959 (to Richard Massey); 11 February 1959; 19 May 1959; 13 August 1959; 21 April 1960 (to S.a
Benjamin Fowler); 19 November 1960 (to John W. Patterson); 16 January 1961; F. 6-19. 1 March 1912; F. 1-9..
Owen, Guy, (3); 1 February 1961; 11 March 1961; 23 December 1961; F. 1-9.
Palmer, Rupert E., (1); 16 January 1914; F. 1-10.
Pierce, Bob, (1); n.d. (to Board of Trustees); F. 6-14.
Pirvics, Juris, (1); 11 September 1959 (to Vanderbilt University Press); F. 3-4.
Poindexter, John W., (1); 11 January 1914; F. 1-10.
Ponder, H.M., Jr., (1); 20 October 1969; F. 6-10.
Ponzine, Raymond E., (1); 24 July 1915; F. 6-16.
Pratt, William C., (3); 18 April 1968; 10 May 1968;" 21 February 1914; F. 1-10.
Purdy, Rob Roy, (8); 14 January 1964; 25 January 1964 (to John H. DeWitt, Jr.; F. 6-18. 8 October 1965; F. 1-10. 11 November 1965 (to John DeWitt, Jr.); F. 6-18. 21 February 1961; F. 1-10. 21 August 1969 (to Charles Nord and George E. Wilkins); F. 6-10. 9 February 1910 (to Nicholas Hobbs); F. 6-2. 12 November 1911; F. 6-1.
Ragland, Charles S., (8); 22 May 1969; 17 June 1969; 20 November 1969; 11 February 1970 (to William Dickson); 16 February 1970 (to H.T. Chandler); 24 February 1970; 24 February 1970 (to William Dickson); 16 March 1970; F. 6-2.
Ragland, Mary Harding (Mrs. Stuart), (1); 16 April 1959; F. 3-5.
Rand, Norfleet H., (2); 23 February 1970; 30 March 1970; F. 6-6.
Randall, Elsie, (1); July 1967; F. 1-10.
Randall, Harry, (1); 2 May 1959; F. 3-5.
Ransom, John Crowe, (2); 16 November 1970 (to Roy P. Basler); 24 November 1970; F. 1-10.
Ream, Mrs. Mary Nelson, (1); 24 April 1959; F. 3-5. Sales Report, (1); 26 July 1976; F. 5-3.
Sanders, lone Overton, (1); Christmas 1975 (card); F. 1-9.
Sanderson, William F., (1); 29 September 1969; F. 6-10.
Shapiro, John L., (1); 29 March 1972; F. 6-7.
SUnpkins, Irby C., Jr., (1); 14 October 1969; F. 6-10.
SUnpson, James A., (6); 30 October 1967; 3 November 1967; F. 6-17. 7 February 1969 (to William S. Vaughn); 17 June 1969; 1 October 1969; 24 October 1969; F. 6-2.
Smith, L.H., (4); 25 February 1957 (to William F. Orr); 20 October 1958 (to John A. Preston); 17 November 1958 (to John H.
Stambaugh); 8 December 1958 (to John H. Stambaugh); F. 6-19.
Smith, Mrs. Mapheus, (1); 15 December 1969; F. 6-13.
Smith, Willa, (1); 6 October 1971; F. 1-10.
Stahlman, James G., (3); 5 June 1965 (to Fort Flowers); F. 6-12. 9 January 1969 (to Harvie Branscomb); F. 6-14. 13 October 1969 (to H. Fort Flowers); F. 6-10.
Stevenson, Alec Brock, (7); 15 October 1961; F. 1-9. 13 April 1965; 11 October 1965 (to Rob Roy Purdy); F. 1-10. 20 March 1966; F. 6-12. 12 July 1966 (to John L. Stewart); F. 1-9. 25 September 1968; F. 6-17. 20 December 1968; F. 6-5.
Stirling, Edwin, (1); 28 August 1974; F. 1-10.
Stokes, Walter, (1); 10 June 1965; F. 6-12.
Sullivan, Walter, (1); 2 April 1968; F. 1-10.
Swint, Henry Lee, (1); 26 September 1972; F. 1-10.
Taber, David Spencer, (2); 22 February 1972; 20 March 1972; F. 1-10.
Tate, Allen, (52); 1 June 1927; 4 June 1958; 6 April 1962; 8 May 1962; 18 May 1962; 21 September 1962 (to Matt Wigginton); 15 February 1966; 18 August 1966; 7 November 1966; 17 November 1966; 21 January 1968; 31 January 1968; 16 February 1968; 22 March 1968; 27 May 1968 (card); 9 June 1968 (card); 29 June 1968 (card); 7 August 1968; 10 September 1968; 17 September 1968; 22 December 1968; 12 January 1969; 7 February 1969; 8 March 1969; 19 March 1969; 11 May 1969; 26 June 1969; 16 July 1969; 10 September 1969; 26 September 1969; 18 March 1970; 7 June 1970; 7 August 1971; 3 May 1972; 1 March 1973; 9 January 1974; 21 January 1974 (card); 17 February 1974 (card); 1 April 1974 (card); 5 April 1974; 29 July 1974; 13 August 1974; 3 October 1974; 20 November 1974; 1 December 1974; 5 January 1975; 17 January 1975; 24 March 1975; 30 October 1975; 26 February 1976; 31 July 1976 (card); F. 1-11, 1-12
Tate, Benjamin, (1); 9 April 1959; F. 1-12.
Tate, Caroline Gordon, (3); 19 December 1975; 26 January 1976; 7 February 1976; F. 1-12.
Tate, Helen (Mrs. Allen), (3); 5 January 1975; 10 November 1975; 3 January 1976; F. 1-12.
Tharp, Peter J., (2); 21 April 1966; 17 May 1966; F. 1-13.
Thist1ethwaite, Donald L., (1); 17 May 1971; F. 6-4.
Thomas, Alexine P., (1); 2 May 1959; F. 3-5.
Thompson, Lawrence S., (1); 19 March 1964; F. 1-12.
Tinsley, Jane, (1); 10 December 1975; F. 5-3.
Trabue, Charles C., Jr., (1); 12 February 1970 (to William S. Vaughn); F. 6-2.
Van Antwerp, Chiles, (1); 17 December 1951; F. 1-13.
Vanderbilt, Harold S., (2); 28 June 1965; F. 6-12. 23 October 1967; F. 6-17..
Vanderbilt William H., (4); 17 April 1969; 14 October 1969; 21 February 1970; F. 6-2. 10 April 1971; F. 6-8.
Vaughn, William S., (15); 3 February 1969; 25 February 1969; 12 June 1969; F. 6-2. 16 October 1969; F. 6-17. 19 November 1969 (to Pace Van Devender); 16 January 1970; 5 February 1970 (to Charles C. Trabue, Jr., and Mrs. Albert Werthan)j 10 February 1970 (to Mrs. Albert Werthan); 26 June 1970; 10 July 1970 (to Merrimon Cuninggim); 10 July 1970; F. 6-2. 9 September 1970 (to William Waller); F. 6-17. 10 November 1971; 19 November 1971; 19 November 1971 (to
John Gaventa); F. 6-2.
Vestermark, Seymour D., (1); 20 November 1957 (to William F. Orr); F. 6 -19.
Walker, Dorothy (Mrs. Marion R.), (1); 14 May 1959; F. 3-5.
Waller, William, (8); 2 November 1967; F. 6-17. 18 February 1969 (to
William S. Vaughn); 21 February 1969; 14 April 1969; 25 September 1969; F. 6-2. 14 September 1970 (to William S. Vaughn); 19 October 1970; F. 6-17. 21 Oct~ber 1970; F. 6-2.
Warren, Austin, (1); 31 January 1976; F. 5-3.
Warren, Robert Penn, (11); 11 May 1956; 8 November 1966; 9 April 1967; 9 June 1967; 14 April 1968; 11 May 1968; 12 June 1969; 16 October 1969; 23 September 197?; 14 October 1972; 8 September 1975;F. 1-13.
Waterman, Steve, (2); 28 October 1976; 19 January 1977; F. 6-11.
Wheelock, John Hall, (1); 5 January 1976; F. 5-3.
Whiteman, Marilyn W., (1); 10 September 1976; F. 1-13.
Wigginton, Matt S., (20); 27 September 1962 (to Allen Tate); 23 December 1964; F. 1-13. 14 December 1967; 31 July 1968; F. 6-13. 7 January 1969; 14 January 1969 (to Frank P. Grisham); 14 January 1969 (to H. Fort Flowers); 21 January 1969; 21 January 1969 (to H. Fort Flowers); F. 6-5. 21 January (to Alexander Heard); F. 6-15. 29 April 1969 (to Frank Grisham); 29 April 1969 (to H. Fort Flowers); F. 6-5. 28 May 1969; 3 June 1969; 3 June 1969; 12 August 1969 (to Edwin S. Gardner); F. 6-13. 7 October 1969 (to Kenneth W. MacKenzie); F. 6-10. 24 April 1970; 30 April 1970; F. 1-13. 15 May 1972; 9 June 1972; F. 1-13. 12 October 1972; 16 August 1976; F. 6-11.
Wilcoxon, Reba, (2); 1 August 1975; 10 October 1975; F. 5-3.
Williams, Fred, (1); 22 April 1959; F. 3-5.
Williams, Margaret, (3); 6 May 1959; F. 3-5. 14 November 1966; 10 August 1970; F. 1-14.
Williamson, John A., (1); 10 November 1969; F. 6-10.
Wills, Elizabeth M., (2); April 1959; F. 3-5. 30 August 1969; F. 1-14.
Wills, Judy (Mrs. Matthew B.), (2); 1 April 1959; 9 April 1959; F. 3-5.
Wills, Ridley, (1); 17 December 1976 (to Harold F. Miller, Jr.); F. 1-14.
Wolfe, Marice, (1); 4 March 1974; F. 1-14.
Woolmer, J. Howard, (2); 27 October 1973 (to Frank P. Grisham); 29 August 1974 (to Frank Grisham); F. 6-13. Young, Thomas Daniel, (23); 15 May 1967; 27 November 1968; 16 January 1969; 5 March 1969; 19 September 1969; 2 October 1969; 10 February 1970; 23 February 1970; (22 December 197Q\; 14 July 1971; 26 July 1971; 19 May 1972; 19 July 1972; 30 August 1972; 13 October 1972; 3 December 1973; Christmas 1973 (card); 9 January 1974; 8 February 1974; 12 July 1974; 6 August 1974; 30 October 1975; [26 May 1976~l; F. 1-14.
Wilcoxon, Reba, (2); 1 August 1975; 10 October 1975; F. 5-3.
Williams, Fred, (1); 22 April 1959; F. 3-5.
Williams, Margaret, (3); 6 May 1959; F. 3-5. 14 November 1966; 10 August 1970; F. 1-14.
Williamson, John A., (1); 10 November 1969; F. 6-10.
Wills, Elizabeth M., (2); April 1959; F. 3-5. 30 August 1969; F. 1-14.
Wills, Judy (Mrs. Matthew B.), (2); 1 April 1959; 9 April 1959; F. 3-5.
Wills, Ridley, (1); 17 December 1976 (to Harold F. Miller, Jr.); F. 1-14.
Wolfe, Marice, (1); 4 March 1974; F. 1-14.
Woo lmer, J. Howard, (2); 27 October 1973 (to Frank P. Grisham); 29 August 1974 (to Frank Grisham); F. 6-13.
Young, Thomas Daniel, May November 7
January March September October 1976'-l; Incomplete signatures: Aurelia, (1); 9 April 1959; F. 3-5. Cousin Carrie, (1); 16 June 1959; F. 3-5. Fanny (to Ellen Wills), (1); 1959; F. 3-5. Julia Fay, (1); 15 April 1959; F. 3-5. No signature: (I); 4 April 1969; F. 1-14.
Miscellaneous essays and reviews by Jesse E. Wills:
Review. The Dream Songs by John Berryman.
Holograph and typed carbon; 1-15.
Review. The Eguilibrist: A Study of John Crowe Ransom's
Poems~ 1916-1963 by Robert Buffington. typed carbon; 1-15.
"Memoirs of Far Hills." typed carbon; 1-15.
"For Coffee House." photocopy; 1-15.
"Professor C.B. Wallace and Wallace School .. " typed carbon; 1-15.
Newspaper clippings:
Donald Davidson
25 April 1968, Obituary Notice; 1-16.
26 April 1968, Nashville Banner: "Davidson Rites Slated; Famed Poet."; 1-16.
26 April 1968, Nashville Tennessean: "Prof. Davidson, 1 Fugitive'. Poet~ Dies at 72.": 1-16..
26 April 1968, Nashville Banner: "Donald Davidson," editorial; 1-16.
27 April 1968, Nashville Tennessean: "Mr. Davidson was Rare Figure," editorial; 1-16.
28 April 1968, Nashville Tennessean: "Gentle and Dear Friend" by Floy Beatty; 1-16.
21 May 1968, National Review: "Donald Davidson, RIP." ;1-16.
24 July 1968, Nashville Banner: IfJUL Acquires Papers of 'Fugitive' Dr. Davidson .. " ;1-16. John Crowe Ransom 6 July 1967, Nashville Tennessean: "Ransom Picked To Receive $10,000 Prize. ff ;1-16.
31 December 1967, Nashville Tennessean: "Ransom Study Most Thorough." Reviewed by Jesse Wills;1-16.
25 April 1969, Nashville Banner: "Writers Conference at Cumberland May 2."; 1-16.
26 April 1968, Nashville Tennessean: "Fugitive To Be Feted on 80th."; 1-16.
29 April 1968, Nashville Banner: "J.C. Ransom, 'Fugitive' To Be Honored."; 1-16. 14 May 1968, Vanderbilt Hustler: "Fugitive John Crowe Ransom Wins Emerson-Thoreau Medal. lf; 1-16. 4 July 1974, Tennessean: "Ransom, Fugitive Poet, Dies."; 1-16. Alec B. Stevenson
27 May 1969, Obituary; 1-16.
27 May 1969, Nashville Banner:"Alec B. Stevenson Dies, Rites at 3 Wednesday."; 1-16.
28 May 1969, Nashville Tennessean: "Alec Stevenson Services Today.lt; 1-16.
28 May 1969, Nashville Banner: "Alec B. Stevenson," editorial; 1-16. 30 May 1969, Nashville Tennessean: "Mr. Stevenson Will Be Missed .. "; 1-16. Eldon Stevenson, Jr. 4 March 1970, Nashville Banner: "vu Names Science Center In Honor of Stevenson." Allen Tate 7August 1966, Nasbyillg Tgnnessean: "Allen Tate Marries Miss Heinz. ,.; 1-16. 12 January 1969,: "Churches To Present U.S. Leaders" by Charles Thompson; 1-16. 1 June 1969, Nashville Tennessean: "Compleat Allen Tate," reviewed by M. Thomas Inge; 1-16. 5 October 1975, Nashville Tennessean: "Allen Tate's Latest Traces His Development" by Sara Morrow; 1-16 ..
28 December 1975, Nashville Tennessean: "Sewanee's Tate Recipient of NY Literary Award. lf; 1-16.
20 May 1976, Nashville Banner: "Allen Tate Awarded National Medal."; 1-16.
n.d., Robert Penn Warren "Allen Tate To Receive Merrill Prize."; 1-16.
Robert Penn Warren
11 April, Nashville Banner: "Three Major Writers, Critics To Speak at VU. tf; 1-16. 19 April 1968, Nashville Banner: "Poetry Symposium Draws Heavy Crowd'at Vanderbilt," by Howell Pearre; 1-16.
19 April 1968, Nashville Tennessean: "'Fugitive' Cites Chaos in Words at VU Talk" by Rhodes Johnston.; 1-16.
31 July 1970, Women's Wear Daily: "Tall, Graceful Eleanor Clark is a Natural," by Brenda Badolato. (Eleanor Clark is Mrs. Robert Penn Warren.); 1-16.
10 November 1974, The Tennessean: "Collected Poems Span Six Years." Review of nOr Else: Poem/Poems 1968-1974." Reviewed by Frances Neel Cheney. 1-16. n. d. ffRobert Penn Warren Wins aBollingen Prize In Poetry.u 1-16.
n.d. "Warren's Poetry Honored." 1-16. Jesse Ely Wills
11 November 1954, Nashville Banner: uPhi Beta Kappa Selection Honors Four VU Alumni." 1-16.
17 January 1971, Nashville Tennessean: "Poet in the Money Making Bu~inessu by Louise Davis. 1-16.
5 November 1971, Nashville Banner: "vu Trustees Elect Two New Life Members.: 1-16.
William R. Wills n~-d. Obituary Notice. 1-16. Others 23 March 1960, Nashville Tennessean: trVU Divinity School
Alumni Ask Lawson Reinstatementff by Edmund Willingham. 1-16.
21 April 1968, Nashville Tennessean: "'Fugitives' Reaffirm Need for Man's Individuality.u 1-16.
23 January 1974, The Tennessean: "Richard Wilbur Slated at Vanderbilt Tonight. 1f 1-16. aPhotographs:
Sculptured bust of Robert Penn Warren by Joan Fitzgerald, four views; 1-17.
Sculptured bust of Ezra Pound by Joan Fitzgerald; 1-17.
Essays, statements by others:
Davidson, Donald. Introduction to Peter Smith reprint of The.Fugitive. typed carbon; 1-18.
Kaser, David. A Fugitive Collection in the Joint University Libraries. typed; 1-18.
Moore, Merrill. On the First Presbyterian Church in Nashville, Tennessee. photocopy, negative; 1-18.a
Taylor, Peter with William Breit, Leland Yeager. James Muir
Waller, 1900-1971. electrostatic copy; 1-18.
Van Antwerp, Chiles. The Old Oak Club. ,mimeograph copy; 1-18.
Reprints, material by others:
Aden, John M. "Student Revolt and the Humani,ties: A NonNegotiable
Dissent." Southern Humanities Review,
Vol. 5, Spring 1971. 1-19.
Jones, David Howell. Announcement of Donald Davidson: An
Essay and ~ Bibliography. l-l~
Tate, Allen. "A Lost Traveller's Dream." Michigan Quarterly
Review, Autumn 1972. 1-19.
Warren, Robert Penn. "Who is Relevant?U Yale Alumni Magazine,
February 1971. 1-19.
Miscellaneous papers:
American Committee for Cultural Freedom. Statement. 1-20.
Mizener Papers. Bill of Sale. 1-20.
Maxey Jarman Kitchen Cabinet. Two Membership cards. 1-20.
SEE NEXT PAGE
The Age We Live In Old Oak Club 1937
America and the Crisis Old Oak Club 1941
The Battle of Midway Old Oak Club 1950
A Business Man Looks at Labor Unions Old Oak Club 1947
Catechism on Present and Future Old Oak Club 1936
Changes on the Weather Coffee House 1957
Old Oak Club 1958
Impressions of a Traveler Concerning Williamsburg, Virginia Old Oak Club 1937
In the Matter of John Masefield The Problems of Air Power Old Oak Club Coffee House Old Oak Club 1969 1943
Prose and Poetry Old Oak Club Coffee House 1961
The Revolutions Around Us Old Oak Club 1965
A Southern Christian Considers Race Old Oak Club 1952
- The list of poems is alphabetically arranged. Those marked with an asterisk appear in the volume, Early and Late, All the 4 poems on this list are contained in Box 2, Folders""
- ♦"Agriochaerus". 1 typescript, 1 carbon
- ♦"Arlington National Cemetary". 1 typescript, holograph note
- ♦"Aunt Minnie I, II, III". 1 typescript
- ♦"Automobile Ride". 1 typescript, 4 carbons
- "Black Sheep". 1 typescript % 1 carbon
- "Changes". 1 typescript, holograph revisions ♦"Consider the Heavens". 2 carbons
- "Crystal Gazer". 2 carbons
- "The Depths". 1 typescript ♦"Dream". 2 holograph, 2 typescript ♦"Dust". 1 typescript, 1 carbon
- "Eden". 2 typescript with holograph revisions, 3 carbons, 1 holograph note
- "False Dawn". 1 typescript, 1 carbon ♦"Fear I, II". 1 typescript entitled "Egomania", 1 carbon
- "Felix Adair". 2 typescript, 4 carbons
- "From a Window". 2 holograph, 1 typescript ♦"A Fundamentalist". 1 typescript, 4 carbons ♦"Healing". 1 typescript, 1 carbon ♦"The Hills Remember". 1 typescript, 2 carbons
- "Lausanne". 1 typescript ♦"Lightning's Blink". 1 typescript, 2 carbons ♦"Night Windows". 2 carbons ♦"Parable". 3 carbons ♦"Premonition", 1 typescript, 1 carbon ♦"Primavera", 1 typescript, 1 carbon
- "The Proposal". 1 typescript with notes in another hand, 3 carbons ♦"Red Even". 3 holograph, 1 carbon ♦"Riddle". 1 holograph, 1 typescript, 2 carbons ♦"Snow Prayers I, II, III". 1 typescript, 3 carbons ♦"The Survivors". 1 carbon
- "Three Rabbits". 1 typescript ♦"To a Tired Clerk". 2 carbons ♦"To the Bugle Not Blown". 1 holograph ♦"Trinity". 1 typescript, 1 carbon
- üntltled poem: "I Tossed an Arm Out...". 1 typescript with holograph
- revision, 1 typescript, 2 carbons. Fragments: 8 pages holograph
- Poems are listed in alphabetical order.
- Location key: J Juvenilia F Fugitive EL Early and Late CP Conversation Piece N Nashville and Other Poems
- "Agriochaerus," F, EL
- "And Fifty Years," CP
- "And Will Be?" EL
- "Arlington National Cemetary," F,EL
- "Armageddon," EL
- "The Artisans," CP
- "Atom End," CP
- "Audubon," N
- "Aunt Minnie," F, EL
- "Automobile Ride," F, EL
- "Bat Magic," EL "Belleek Valentine," EL "Biography," N "Black Sheep," F "Boy and Bird," N "Bystander," CP
- "Canticle for Animals," N
- "Cape Cod, 1960," CP
- "Casual Reference, Book Obscure," CP
- "Centuries," N
- "Changes," F
- "Conjunction," CP
- "Consider the Heavens," F, EL
- "Contrast," J
- "Conversation Piece," CP
- "Crystal Gazer," F
- "Deliver Us," N "The Depths," F "Devil's Advocate," EL "Discovery," EL "Domina," N "Double View," J "Dream," F, EL "Dust," F, EL
- "Eden," F
- "Estes Park, 1919," J
- "Evening Grosbeak," CP
- "Extinction," J
- "Ex-Wizardry," J
- "Fall Mockery," CP
- "False Dawn," F
- "Fear," F, EL
- "Felix Adair," F
- "Final Note," N
- "The Flesh of Flowers," EL
- "For a Daughter," CP
- "For My Father," N
- "Form and Formless," N
- "From a Window," F
- "Full Circle," CP
- "A Fundamentalist," F, EL
- "The Generations," N "Gone," N "Gray," CP "Green," N
- "The Half Men," EL
- "Half Said," CP
- "Happenstances," N
- "The Happy Home," J
- "Harbor Changes," N
- "Healing," F, EL
- "Hermitage," CP